{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "An instrument detects the presence of electric current in the circuit, is known as,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Galvanometer",
        "b": "Voltmeter",
        "c": "Rheostat",
        "d": "Wattmeter"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a D’Arsonval galvanometer what is the purpose of using iron core between two pole faces?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The effect of stray magnetic field is reduced",
        "b": " Moment of inertia of moving parts become smaller",
        "c": "Cost of production is reduced",
        "d": "Flux density in the air gap becomes high, causing large deflecting torque"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the most common absolute instrument that gives the measured current in form of tangent of deflected angle?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Tangent Galvanometer",
        "b": "Tangent Voltmeter",
        "c": "Tangent Rheostat",
        "d": "Tangent Wattmeter"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Galvanometer connected with high resistance in series is used as",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Ohmmeter",
        "b": "Ammeter",
        "c": "Wattmeter",
        "d": "Voltmeter"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Sometimes D’Arsonval galvanometer do not use ferromagnetic cores between the poles of permanent magnet, in this case,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The flux density becomes smaller, resulting in low deflecting torque",
        "b": "The dimension of moving coil can be made smaller, thereby reducing Moment of inertia.",
        "c": "The magnetic field may not be radial, resulting in a non-uniform scale even if spring control is used.",
        "d": "All the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": " Which one of the following galvanometers used for deflection of current?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Ballistic galvanometer",
        "b": "Dead-beat galvanometer",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": " None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },	
	
	
	{
      "question": " Which one of the following meters is a type of electromechanical device?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Galvanometer",
        "b": "Ammeter",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
	 "question": "The advantages of using galvanometers are ___________?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "High accuracy",
        "b": "High reliability",
        "c": "High sensitivity",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
	 "question": "The mechanical hysteresis is an example for ______________ damping?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " Material damping",
        "b": "Hydraulic damping",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
	 "question": "Which one of the following components are used in ballistic galvanometer?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Permanent magnets",
        "b": "Spring",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
  ]
}
